

Research Summary

My research aims to develop *reliable* and *responsible* Machine learning (ML) algorithms, especially in real-world scenarios such as healthcare. **Reliable ML** not only provides accurate predictions, but also adheres to robustness, fairness, and transparency, thus instilling confidence in its use and outcomes. (see more in AI Safety). **Responsible ML** ensures ethical decision-making and equitable outcomes while considering the broader societal impact. (see more in Responsible ML).

Education

Université Laval	Canada
Ph.D in Electrical Engineering	2017.05-2022.03
Supervisors: Prof. Christian Gagné, Prof. Boyu Wang	
Université Paris Saclay	France
Master in Applied Mathematics, Affiliated to École Normale Supérieure Paris Saclay	2015.09-2016.10
cum laude, 14.75/20	
Télécom ParisTech	France
Diplôme d'ingenieur	2013.08-2015.06
Southeast University	China
Bachelor of Electronic Science and Engineering	2009.07-2013.06

Working Experience

Vector Institute
Postdoctoral Fellow
Mentor: Rahul G. Krishnan

Toronto, Canada
2023.12-Now

McGill UniversityMontreal, CanadaPostdoctoral Fellow, Affiliated to Mila (Quebec AI Institute)2022.05-2023.05

Supervisor: Prof. Tal Arbel

Selected Publications

Detailed publications can be found in Google Scholar

Reliable Machine Learning.....

- On the Stability-Plasticity Dilemma in Continual Meta-Learning: Theory and Algorithm. Qi Chen, Changjian Shui, Ligong Han, Mario Marchand. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023, acceptance rate = 26.1%
- On Learning Fairness and Accuracy on Multiple Subgroups. Changjian Shui, Gezheng Xu, Qi Chen, Jiaqi Li, Charles Ling, Tal Arbel, Boyu Wang, Christian Gagné. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022, acceptance rate = 25.6%
- o Fair Representation Learning through Implicit Path Alignment. Changjian Shui, Qi Chen, Jiaqi Li, Boyu Wang, Christian Gagné. International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2022,

 $acceptance\ rate = 21.9\%$

- Generalization Bounds For Meta-Learning: An Information-Theoretic Analysis. Qi Chen, Changjian Shui, Mario Marchand. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021, spotlight, 3% of the submissions.
- o On the benefits of representation regularization in invariance based domain generalization. Changjian Shui, Boyu Wang and Christian Gagné. *Machine Learning Journal (MLJ)*, 2022.

Applications.....

- o Latent Trajectory Learning for Limited Timestamps under Distribution Shift over Time Qiuhao Zeng, Changjian Shui, Long-Kai Huang, Peng Liu, Xi Chen, Charles Ling, and Boyu Wang. International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2024, oral, 1.2% of the submissions.
- Mitigating Calibration Bias Without Fixed Attribute Grouping for Improved Fairness in Medical Imaging Analysis. Changjian Shui, Justin Szeto, Raghav Mehta, Douglas Arnold, Tal Arbel. International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2023, early acceptance rate= 14%
- Aggregating From Multiple Target-Shifted Sources. Changjian Shui, Zijian Li, Jiaqi Li, Christian Gagné, Charles Ling, Boyu Wang. International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021, acceptance rate = 21.5%
- Deep Active Learning: Unified and Principled Method for Query and Training. Changjian Shui, Fan Zhou, Christian Gagné, Boyu Wang. International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS), 2020, acceptance rate = 28.7%

PhD Thesis

Principled deep learning approaches for learning limited labeled data through distribution matching

Université Laval, Quebec, 2022.03

Evaluation committee: Aaron Courville, Mario Marchand, Thierry Duchesne

Honors and Awards

- Vector Postdoctoral Fellowship.
- UNIQUE Conference Travel Grants (Unifying Neuroscience and Artificial Intelligence, Québec), 2023
- o Expert Reviewer, TMLR, 2023
- o Travel Grant Award, NeurIPS, 2022
- o Top Reviewer Award (Top 10%), NeurIPS, 2022
- o Honorable Prize, Presentation in Semaine NumériQC, Québec, 2022
- o Highlighted Reviewer Award (Top 10%), ICLR, 2022
- o Outstanding Reviewer Award (Top 8%), NeurIPS, 2021
- o Best Reviewer Award (Top 10%), ICML, 2021

- o Outstanding Reviewer Award (Top 10%), ICLR, 2021
- o Top 25% Reviewer, AAAI, 2021
- o 3rd Prize, Presentation in Journée de la relève en intelligence et données, Québec, 2021
- o Travel Grant Award, IJCAI, 2019
- o Scholarships of Insitut Mines-Télécom, 2013-2014

Research blogs

- o Invariance and Learning Fair Representation
- o Fast sequential decision-making via prior knowledge

Skills

Programming LanguagesMATLAB, Python, Latex , C/C++, HMTL, JAVALibraryPytorch, Tensorflow, JAX

Languages.....

- o Chinese (Mother language)
- English (Advanced)
- o French (Advanced)